Matthew Green

London, United Kingdom

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Experienced in hotel management at 5 star level, from large chain hotels in busy capital cities of London and Dublin, including Airport Hotels. Qualified to degree level in Hospitality Management. Experienced in Guest Relations, Food and Beverage, Sales and Revenue, and Front Office. Strong Hilton Background, including pre-opening experience. Currently studying part-time Full Stack Software Development with Code Institute to improve IT skills

mattgreen91@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/mattgreen91



EDUCATION

Code Institute, Dublin – (2020 – Present) University of West London, Ealing (2011-13) Franklin Sixth Form College, Grimsby (2007-09) Queen Elizabeth's Grammar, Alford (2002-07)

QUALIFICATIONS

FdA Degree in Hospitality Management – University Distinction in MDP1 (Hilton Management Program) Hilton Qualified Brand Trainer (EMEA)

KEY SKILLS

Leadership, Communication, Organisation, Yield Management, Revenue Generation, Customer Service, Technological, Analytical, Self-Motivated

IT SKILLS

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Access) Opera PMS, OnQ PM, OnQ R&I, Delphi, IDeaS, Micros HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, React JS, VB.Net, Python, Flask, MongoDB, Django, SQL

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front Desk Manager (Pre-Opening)

Curio by Hilton, London (4 star 126 rooms), February 2020 – Present

- Training and Development of Systems and Procedures, ensuring team have Brand Awareness
- Creating SOPs and Training plans, and implementing new Health & Safety policies due to Covid 19
- Monitoring trends on SALT and Tripadvisor, to prevent same issues recurring
- Responsible for Health & Safety, Disability Awareness, and First Aid
- Creating and sending out RMY report daily to RMCC

Night Manager (Brand Conversion)

Westin (Marriott Hotels & Resorts) Dublin (5 star 172 rooms), August 2018 – September 2019

- Using Yield Management Skills to modify rates depending on demand, such as LOS / Value level,
 with the target of maximising occupancy whilst maintaining high ADR
- Introduced Room Upgrades to drive RevPAR by an additional 3.4%
- Proactively responding to Guest Satisfaction Surveys and Guest Alerts within 24 hours, to eliminate
 any loss in revenue due to potential service recovery. In addition, monitoring all reviews on
 Revinate, and addressing any recurring issues to the relevant HODs.
- Responsible for whole hotel during night shift, ensuring hotel is safe and secure, including monitoring events which pass into night-time, such as Weddings or Christmas parties

Groups, Conference & Events Sales Executive

Hilton Dublin Airport (4 star 166 rooms), November 2017 – August 2018

- Received and converted 40% of enquiries to achieve targets and maximise revenue
- Reduced number of Turned-Down bookings by 20% with proactive follow-ups
- €100k quarterly sales target achieved in 3 out of 4 quarters
- Increased conversion of Prospect bookings into Tentative status by additional 30%
- Manage events schedule to maximise yield
- Building relationships with customers, and negotiating to secure business on a win-win basis
- Performing show-rounds, creating Event Agreements, Contracts, Proformas, Banquet Event Orders
- Using IDeaS to quote bedroom rates for non-transient bookings of 8+ bedrooms
- Programming Delphi with menu updates, and sending out Catering Production Report to RMCC
- Graduated with Distinction for Hilton MDP1 Project, and successfully implemented, which has increased Parking Revenue by an additional 20%, maintaining a Return on Investment of 4% in the first year

Assistant Front Office Manager

Hilton Dublin Airport (4 star 166 rooms), August 2014 – November 2017

- Contacting future reservations in advanced to achieve sell-out efficiency 80% of the time
- Ensuring daily threshold of 96% is met 95% of the year, by proactively contacting other hotels who are overbooked
- Introduced Wildly Important Goals and Lead Measures driving SALT Overall Performance from average of 58% to 70%, by implementing high quality customer service techniques
- Increased target Hilton Honors Enrolments to 10 per day, and motivated the team to achieve this target 95% of the time
- Dealing direct with suppliers, ordering stock using BirchStreet
- Responsibilities of Quality Assurance, assisting with passing QA test through compliance
- Preparing staff roster, and weekly payroll using Watson, and performing weekly forecasting
- Attending Daily Detail call, to discuss previous bedroom revenue, and strategy for today
- Attended RMCC Open Day to get a better insight into how RMCC works for Hilton
- Conducted New Hire Orientation training all new team members as per Brand Standards

Guest Relations Manager

DoubleTree by Hilton Dublin (4 star 501 rooms), March 2014 - August 2014

- Checking function sheets regularly, and ensuring all events are running smoothly
- Meeting and greeting VIP clients on arrival, to encourage them to rebook
- Fixing/reporting any issues, dealing with complaints, and following up to ensure minimal impact on service recovery revenue loss
- Empowerment to make any major decisions in the absence of senior management
- Conduction PDRs and PDPs for team members
- Regularly conducting initial stages of Interview & Selection with Human Resources

Food and Beverage Manager

Mercure, Hull (3 star, 160 rooms), August 2013 – February 2014

- Duty manager on majority of shifts
- Running events/conferences, and all food & beverage outlets
- Purchase ordering and cellar Balancing on a weekly basis
- Creating rota, payroll, approving holidays using Forth Hospitality
- Training & development, appraisals/performance reviews